<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DACAS Lab - DACAS Group</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/dacas-group.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2023-01-31T00:00:00+11:00</updated><entry><title>Paper accepted in AIAA SciTech</title><link href="/paper-accepted-in-aiaa-scitech.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-31T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2023-01-31T00:00:00+11:00</updated><author><name>DACAS Group</name></author><id>tag:None,2023-01-31:/paper-accepted-in-aiaa-scitech.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our paper titled, "Constant Optical Flow Divergence based Robust Adaptive Control Strategy for Autonomous Vertical Landing of Quadrotors" was accepted at AIAA SciTech&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2 id="link-to-the-paper"&gt;Link to the paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arc.aiaa.org/doi/abs/10.2514/6.2023-1150"&gt;Constant Optical Flow Divergence based Robust Adaptive Control Strategy for Autonomous Vertical Landing of Quadrotors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An autonomous unmanned aerial vehicle can be influenced by possibly unknown model uncertainties and exogenous perturbations. The primary sources of model uncertainties in an autonomous vehicle are noise and time delay in sensor measurements; however, an aerial vehicle is also exposed to exogenous perturbations due to wind gusts and ground effects (especially in the case of a quadrotor). This study proposes a novel control strategy for the soft landing of a quadrotor onto a textured stationary landing platform without any prior information on the model uncertainties and exogenous perturbations present in the system dynamics. The proposed controller employs the divergence of the optical flow field with the fundamental purpose of executing a constant flow divergence landing maneuver while driving the vertical velocity of the quadrotor to zero. The output error is subjected to prescribed performance constraints to achieve the desired transient and steady-state behaviour of the proposed controller. The design of this controller is based on proportional-integral (PI) sliding mode and a state-dependent control law that synthesizes continuous control actions to ensure finite-time convergence of the output error to a uniform ultimate bound. The critical control law is based on adaptive first-order sliding mode, where the control gains are designed to adapt to the unknown uncertainties and perturbations online. This control law also helps in attaining the finite-time convergence to a prespecified bound that is independent of the size of the uncertainties and perturbations. Subsequently, Lyapunov analysis is performed to demonstrate the global stability of the proposed control strategy. Numerical simulation results are presented to exhibit the effectiveness and robustness of the proposed control approach for different initial conditions in the presence of uncertainties and perturbations. Lastly, a performance comparison analysis is conducted with a fixed-gain PI controller to demonstrate the superiority of the proposed adaptive gain controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="video-presentation"&gt;Video Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View Video Presentation: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2514/6.2023-1150.vid"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blogposts"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper accepted in IEEE Access</title><link href="/paper-accepted-in-ieee-access.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-09-12T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>DACAS Group</name></author><id>tag:None,2022-09-12:/paper-accepted-in-ieee-access.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our paper titled, "A Provably Constrained Neural Control Architecture With Prescribed Performance for Fault-Tolerant Redundant Manipulators" was accepted at IEEE Access&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2 id="link-to-paper"&gt;Link to paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/9888126"&gt;A Provably Constrained Neural Control Architecture With Prescribed Performance for Fault-Tolerant Redundant Manipulators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper, a novel neural control architecture is proposed and investigated for resolving redundancy in trajectory tracking applications for manipulators with joint velocity constraints. First, a nonlinear invertible map is invoked to transform the constrained system state into a set of unconstrained variables, which allows the proposed framework to realize solutions that rigorously adhere to the specified bound constraints. Next, a quadratic program (QP) architecture is synthesized by incorporating suitably prescribed performance constraints to ensure that the resulting system error achieves exponential convergence to the ground truth while also ensuring that the system states evolve along trajectories with good transient and steady-state behavior. Thus, in contrast with previous approaches that do not rigorously guarantee the satisfaction of the bound constraints in the transient phase and/or the steady-state, the proposed scheme ensures that these constraints are rigorously satisfied while achieving prescribed performance both during the transient phase and in the steady-state. The novelty of the proposed scheme lies in the fusion of prescribed performance constraints with the state and input constraints within the QP framework, which offers the important advantage of higher computational efficiency compared to leading alternative designs. A detailed theoretical analysis is undertaken to prove the global stability and convergence of the proposed scheme. Simulation and experimental results with the KUKA LBR IIWA 14 R820 manipulator are used to verify the efficacy of the proposed scheme in accomplishing trajectory tracking for the fault-free and fault-tolerant cases with multiple joint failures. Finally, detailed performance comparison studies with leading alternative designs are further used to illustrate the advantages of the proposed scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="blogposts"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper accepted in IEEE Transactions on Industrial Informatics</title><link href="/paper-accepted-in-ieee-transactions-on-industrial-informatics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-14T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T00:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>DACAS Group</name></author><id>tag:None,2022-06-14:/paper-accepted-in-ieee-transactions-on-industrial-informatics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our paper titled, "Prescribed Performance Control for Solving Time-Varying Underdetermined Linear Systems With Bounds on States and their Derivatives" was accepted at IEEE Transactions on Industrial Informatics&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2 id="link-to-paper"&gt;Link to paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/9795906"&gt;Prescribed Performance Control for Solving Time-Varying Underdetermined Linear Systems With Bounds on States and their Derivatives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper addresses the problem of finding online solutions to time-varying underdetermined linear systems with limits on states and their derivatives through a novel zeroing neural network (ZNN) implementation. The proposed model combines zeroing dynamics with user-prescribed performance constraints to ensure that the system achieves desired transient and steady-state behavior. The novelty of this approach lies in a nonlinear invertible mapping that transforms the constrained system to an unconstrained one so that the resulting error remains subsequently bounded by the performance function for all time. In particular, two different ZNN models are synthesized that rely on an exponentially convergent and finite-time convergent performance function to drive the residual error to convergence. The effectiveness of the proposed models is verified through redundancy resolution in path tracking problems in robotics. A detailed performance comparison study with two leading alternative designs is also undertaken to further illustrate the merits of the proposed schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="blogposts"></category></entry><entry><title>Paper accepted in IFToMM Asian conference on Mechanism and Machine Science</title><link href="/paper-accepted-in-iftomm-asian-conference-on-mechanism-and-machine-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-12-15T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2021-12-15T00:00:00+11:00</updated><author><name>DACAS Group</name></author><id>tag:None,2021-12-15:/paper-accepted-in-iftomm-asian-conference-on-mechanism-and-machine-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our paper titled, "Finite-Time Formation Convergence of Vision-Based Nonholonomic Systems Without Explicit Communication" was accepted at the IFToMM Asian conference on Mechanism and Machine Science&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2 id="link-to-paper"&gt;Link to paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-91892-7_42"&gt;Finite-Time Formation Convergence of Vision-Based Nonholonomic Systems Without Explicit Communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study considers the problem of synthesizing a decentralized control policy for leader-follower formation tracking of a group of nonholonomic agents in the absence of explicit inter-agent communication. Each follower robot is equipped with a perspective camera, and by tracking a single point feature attached to the leader agent, the leader-follower formation kinematics is developed in the image space of the follower agent. An adaptive continuous sliding mode controller is then proposed for the follower agent, and it is shown that the resulting closed-loop observer-controller system achieves global finite-time convergence of the tracking error to a small uniform ultimate bound around the origin in the absence of either explicit measurement/estimation of the leader agent&amp;rsquo;s position and velocity. Furthermore, it is shown that the size of this error bound can be arbitrarily reduced through a sufficiently large choice of the controller gain. Simulation results are used to validate and demonstrate robust performance of the proposed scheme in the presence of measurement noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="blogposts"></category></entry></feed>